# Sean Collins

Long Beach, CA

J +1-562-370-0806 ■ sean.collins.developer@gmail.com in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sean-collins-4a6279252/

https://github.com/drink-some-water

# **Summary**

A versatile Junior Software Developer with over one year of web development experience at small and large enterprises. Experienced with a range of projects from greenfield development in research, to working with legacy code and Agile processes at startups. Responsible, in part, for startup receiving advertisement funding from Google due to exceptional performance metrics. Used my unique research experience to help the development team deploy their new site over AWS. Primary skills include React/JavaScript, SQL, and Python/Django, especially for Software Developer in Test (SDET) roles. Worked closely with Machine Learning developers labeling AI training data. After some time, selected to oversee other data annotators and design new training data points.

# **Work Experience**

Data Annotation.tech Jan 2024 - Present

Software Developer

Remote

- Rated and corrected AI-generated code responses for truthfulness, instruction adherence, and quality, leading to selection for unique projects and peer review tasks.
- Unit tested code samples in JavaScript, React, SQL, and Python, contributing to improved AI training data.
- Quickly learned new libraries and concepts within 55 minute time limit, writing sufficiently researched bug reports to serve the senior members of the team.

#### **Our National Conversation**

Feb 2024 - Apr 2024

Software Developer Intern

Los Angeles, CA

- Assisted in the deployment of the new website over AWS, teaching several best practices along the way. New technologies included EC2, S3, Elastic Beanstalk, and DynamoDB to handle the basic site functions and Elastic Load Balancing and Route 53 for site scalability.
- Translated Wordpress website into a React/Django MVC web application. Contributions lead to the project achieving performance metrics necessary to receive startup funding from Google.
- Met regularly with shareholders to evaluate prototypes and discuss project direction, becoming one of the key speakers in software development meetings.

#### California State University - Long Beach

May 2023 - Dec 2023

Long Beach, CA

- Teaching Assistant Distributed Computing
  - Compiled dozens of data science research papers into lecture slides, introducing students to topics such as data integration, master data management, data federation, and ontology. Material continues to be used in classes after my graduation.
  - Graded labs on a variety of topics, mostly tutorials on Google Compute Engine and AWS. Labs included creating virtual private clouds with features like load balancing for client-server applications.
- Created new labs to expose students to search engine technology, including a stream-querying project using Apache Kafka. Some students kept in touch and went on to apply these skills in their careers.

#### **Education**

## California State University - Long Beach

2021 - 2023

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Long Beach, California

- **GPA**: 3.5
- Achievements: Presidents Honor List
- Coursework: Machine Learning, Cloud Distributed Computing, UI/UX, Project Management/Software Development Lifecycle

## **Skills**

- Languages: C++, Python, HTML, Jupyter, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, BigQuery), JavaScript, Java, C#
- Frameworks: React, .NET, Spring, Django
- Technologies: AWS, Compute Engine, Jira, Git, Agile methodologies, Apache Flink, Kafka, Docker